<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE phrases SYSTEM "entities.dtd">
<epp:phrases xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:epp="http://eprints.org/ep3/phrase" xmlns:epc="http://eprints.org/ep3/control">

<epp:phrase id="Plugin/InputForm/Component/REF2029:title">REF2029 OA Compliance</epp:phrase>

<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_ex_dep">Deposit Exceptions</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldopt_ref2029_ex_dep_a">It would be unlawful to deposit, or request the deposit of, the output or to otherwise make this available.</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldopt_ref2029_ex_dep_b">The publication actively disallows open access deposit in a repository and was the most appropriate publication for the output.</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldopt_ref2029_ex_dep_c">Subject to delay in securing the final peer-reviewed text for deposit – for instance, where a paper has multiple authors.</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_ex_dep_txt">Deposit Exceptions Reason</epp:phrase>

<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_ex_acc">Access Exceptions</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldopt_ref2029_ex_acc_a">The publication requires an embargo period that exceeds the stated maxima and was the most appropriate publication for the output. Outputs will not need to meet the embargo requirements in this case.</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldopt_ref2029_ex_acc_b">Third-party content was included for which licences could not be obtained at a reasonable cost. The output will not need to meet access and/or licensing requirements (as relevant) in this case.</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_ex_acc_txt">Access Exceptions Reason</epp:phrase>

<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_ex_tec">Technical Exceptions</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldopt_ref2029_ex_tec_a">Output has a demonstrable and substantive connection to the submitting institution but was published following the end of the author’s period of employment, and it has not been possible to determine compliance with the criteria.</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldopt_ref2029_ex_tec_b">Outputs were authored in whole by one or more staff who are or were ineligible to be included in the volume measure for REF 2029. The funding bodies have agreed this exception across the publication period for REF 2029 in order to support submission of a wide range of eligible outputs.</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_ex_tec_txt">Technical Exceptions Reason</epp:phrase>

<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_ex_fur">Further Exception</epp:phrase>
<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_ex_fur_txt">Further Exceptions Reason</epp:phrase>


<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_pub_agreement">License exception due to publication agreement</epp:phrase>

<epp:phrase id="ref2029_cc_fieldname_ref2029_gold_oa">Gold/Diamond/Platinum OA</epp:phrase>

</epp:phrases>
